The increasing prevalence of diabetes in the 21st century is a problem, an epidemic even.
在 21 世纪 日渐升高的糖尿病患病率是个大问题 糖尿病甚至可以说是一种流行病
Pre 1920s, diabetes was a feared disease,
在 20 世纪 20 年代之前 人们闻糖尿病色变
that most certainly led to death.
因为患病就几乎等于死亡
Doctors knew what it was,
医生知道这种病
uncontrollable and often elevated blood sugar levels,
无法控制 而且通常会导致血糖升高
but not how to treat it, let alone cure it.
但不知道要如何治疗 更不用说治愈了
This meant patients dealt with symptoms like unusual thirst,
糖尿病患者病征有如 异常口渴、
frequent urination, extreme fatigue,
尿频、极度疲劳
and also more serious complications like stroke,
甚至有更严重的并发症 如中风、
blindness, loss of limbs,
失明、截肢、
kidney failure, and even heart attack.
肾衰竭甚至心肌梗塞
Luckily, in the 1920s,
好在到了 20 世纪 20 年代
a secretion in the pancreas that lowered blood sugar levels,
一种能降血糖的胰腺分泌物
soon to be called insulin,
即一种很快被命名为胰岛素的物质
was discovered by soon to be Nobel Prize winner Frederick Banting.
被很快就成为诺贝尔奖得主的 Frederick Banting 发现了
This is how insulin works.
以下是胰岛素的作用机理
Most of the food we eat is turned to glucose,
我们吃下的大多数食物都会转化为葡萄糖
or sugar, for our bodies to use for energy.
也就是糖分 为我们的身体供能
The pancreas, an organ near the stomach,
而在胃附近有个器官叫胰腺
makes a hormone called insulin,
会生成一种叫胰岛素的激素
to help glucose get into the cells of our bodies.
该激素能促进葡萄糖被人体细胞吸收
When you have diabetes,
如果你得了糖尿病
your body either doesn't make enough insulin
就意味着你的身体无法分泌足够的胰岛素
or can't use its own insulin as well as it should.
或是无法发挥体内胰岛素的正常功能
And this causes sugars to build-up in the blood.
血液中的糖分由此增多
With Banting discovery of insulin,
Banting 一发现了胰岛素
pharmaceutical companies began large-scale production of insulin almost immediately.
制药公司几乎就立刻开始大规模生产它
Although it doesn't cure diabetes,
虽然胰岛素不能治愈糖尿病
it's one of the biggest discoveries in medicine.
但仍为医学史上最大的发现之一
When it came, it was like a miracle.
它的出现仿佛是个奇迹
People with severe diabetes,
那些患有严重糖尿病
and only days left to live were saved,
只剩几天可活的人 被胰岛素救了下来
but the default method of administration back then was a needle,
不过在当时 胰岛素默认是用针管注射的
multiple times a day, and it still is now.
一天要注射多次 到了今日都是如此
This is scary for some people and uncomfortable and inconvenient for the vast majority.
这对于某些人来说很可怕 对于大部分人来说 很不舒服也很不方便
Insulin pumps are a more recent invention.
后来发明了胰岛素泵
These are insulin delivering devices that are
这是一种胰岛素输入装置
semi-permanently connected to a diabetics body.
会半永久地连接在糖尿病患者身上
But wouldn't it be great if diabetics could take insulin orally,
可要是糖尿病人能口服胰岛素
carrying around a pocketable packet of pills,
把药丸放在口袋里随身携带 那该多好啊
rather than a kit of vials and needles or wearing a bulky somewhat uncomfortable device?
这可比一套针瓶针头 或带着有些不舒服的碍事装置好多了吧？
The future. Oral insulin.
因此 未来 口服胰岛素
This is an active area of research,
这是个活跃的研究领域
and has been for a long time.
而且长期以来都是如此
Historically though there's been a big roadblock,
然而从过去看来 这个领域有颗很大的拦路石
getting insulin through the stomachs thick lining.
让胰岛素通过厚厚的胃粘膜
In these next two lessons,
接下来的两节课
we've got our hands on the phase two clinical trial data
我们将接触一份 II 期临床试验数据
for a new innovative oral insulin called auralin.
涉及一种革新性的新型口服胰岛素 叫 Auralin
Auralin researchers believe their proprietary capsule
Auralin 研究人员认为他们的专利胶囊
will solve this stomach lining problem.
能解决这一胃粘膜问题
Phase two trials test the efficacy and the dose response of a drug,
II 期试验会对药品的功效和剂量反应进行测试
plus identify common short term side effects,
还会找出药品常见的短期副作用
also known as adverse reactions.
也即不良反应
These typically involve several hundred patients.
这种试验通常会涉及数百位患者
In this trial, we have 350,
在这次试验中 我们有 350 名患者
split into two groups.
分为两组
One hundred seventy five or half treated with the new oral insulin auralin,
其中一百七十五人 也就是一半的患者 使用新型口服胰岛素 Auralin 进行治疗
and the other 175 being treated with the popular injectable insulin called novodra.
另外 175 人则用市面流行的注射型胰岛素 Novodra 进行治疗
By comparing key metrics between these two drugs,
通过比较这两种药物的关键指标
we can determine if auralin is effective.
我们可以判定 Auralin 是否有效
The most important metric,
最重要的指标
HbA1c levels, and specifically, HbA1c change.
为 HbA1c 水平 在本表格中记为 hba1c_change
This sounds super technical,
是不是听起来太专业了
and it kind of is,
的确有点
but don't let it intimidate you.
但是你也别害怕
HbA1c is a property of the blood that measures how
HbA1c 是血液中的一种物质 能够衡量
well your blood sugar levels have been controlled over the past few months.
过去几个月来人体血糖水平的控制情况
With higher levels, being bad.
如果该指标高 那就不是好事
If auralin, the new oral insulin,
如果新型口服胰岛素 Auralin
can reduce HbA1c_levels at a similar standard as
能让 HbA1c 的水平从某些试验前标准基线降至
the injectable insulin novodra from some standard pretrial baseline,
与注射型胰岛素 Novodra 所降程度相似的水平
like say they both decrease HbA1c_levels from 7.9% to 7.4%,
打个比方 假设 HbA1c 水平为 7.9% 如果两种药物都能将其降为 7.4%
that's a 0.5% drop.
也就是使其下降 0.5%
If we can get a 0.4 change,
就算新药造成的变化只有 0.4
we've got ourselves a major medical breakthrough,
都是个巨大的医学突破了
in the dramatic quality of life improvement for diabetics all over the world.
能够大幅提高全球糖尿病患者的生活质量
Before we can get to that point of recommendation though,
不过在我们推荐药品之前
we've got ourselves another problem.
还有另一个问题
Healthcare data is notorious for its errors and disorganization,
医疗数据臭名昭著 因为经常出错 而且杂乱不堪
and its clinical trial data is no exception.
这份临床试验数据也不例外
For example, human errors during
比如 病人登记过程出现人为错误
the patient registration process means we can have duplicate data,
会造成数据冗余、
missing data and inaccurate data.
缺失或是不准确
And this common healthcare data issue is reflected in this clinical trial data.
医疗数据的这些典型问题都在这份临床试验数据中有所体现
In this lesson, you're going to take the first step in fixing these issues.
在本课程中 你将踏上解决这些问题的第一步
You're going to assess this data sets quality and tidiness,
你将评估这个数据集的质量和整洁度
and take note of all of these issues.
记下所有问题
In the next lesson,
到了下一节课
you'll then clean all of these issues using Python and Pandas.
你将用 Python 和 pandas 来解决所有问题
The end goal, being able to create a trustworthy analysis.
我们的最终目的就是实现可信的数据分析
And hopefully, eventually recommend this new drug,
但愿我们最终能推荐这款新药
this new oral insulin,
这款新型口服胰岛素
to continue to large-scale production and
能够被投入大规模生产
improve the lives of diabetics all over the world.
从而提高全球糖尿病患者的生活质量